# Wesley Mbate

**Tel:** +4915734560680

Email: wesleymbate@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wesley-mbate-b1b206177

Github: <a href="https://github.com/Wess58">https://github.com/Wess58</a>

Portfolio: bit.ly/wessfolio

#### About

I am a software developer with five years of experience in front-end engineering, eager to advance my career skills in the software engineering field and join an innovative and exciting company. Using my skills to create products that benefit the community and improve human well-being is my passion.

## Professional career

#### **Meliora Technologies Limited**, Nairobi (Kenya) Lead Frontend Developer

August 2022 - to present

- Providing leadership and facilitating in sharing company technical docs of knowledge in best practices within the Frontend engineering department through close collaboration and mentorship for in-house engineers and interns
- Delivered high-quality, robust production code for a diverse array of projects for corporate clients and internal services
- Worked alongside software engineers to lead the research, development of technical solutions to fulfill business requirements.
- Collaborated with designers, project managers, and other engineers to transform creative concepts into software for clients eg: KCB Bank

#### Meliora Technologies Limited, Nairobi (Kenya)

#### Frontend Developer

August 2019 - August 2022

- Delivered high-quality, robust production code for a diverse array of projects for corporate clients
- Collaborated with senior developers and other project players to transform concepts into software for internal use primarily using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

#### Meliora Technologies Limited, Nairobi (Kenya)

Internship Software Engineering

March 2019 - July 2019

- Collaborated, maintained and shipped and ongoing project to production a tour-management service for a Tour agent company
- Worked alongside software engineers to help build my confidence in problem solving skills and project design skills

# Noteworthy projects

#### MySerrari - 2023 to date

Using Angular Ionic for the front-end and spring boot for the back-end, we developed a product that helps users improve their Financial literacy and management. The product offers features such as Monthly-spend planning with a transparent and easy payment experience allowing users to track expenses and budget their income. Wealth instruments and Networth Tracking that provide information and guidance on how to grow assets and liabilities. Assets and Document registry for convenient storage and access to important financial documents and records. The product's goal is to enhance financial growth, confidence and competence by providing awareness of financial literacy and enhanced financial opportunities and outcomes to regular citizens, businesses and investment groups.

#### Bake Connect - 2022 to date

Bake Connect is an Angular-based web application that I developed for home bakers to streamline their business operations. It enables users to handle orders, payments, as well as send tailored notifications via SMS. The app also provides payment tracking, Generating and sending quotations & invoices to customers, Expenses & income tracking with user-friendly analytic dashboards and Shopping list management. The app has received positive feedback from its users, who have reported that the app has enhanced their business performance, customer interaction & satisfaction, maintaining professionalism and improving their quality of services.

#### **Kekes Reading Nook - 2022**

As the lead front-end developer, we built an Angular-based platform using TypeScript and Bootstrap, with a spring boot backend. The platform enables users to rent books from a wide genre selection, based on their subscription plan, from a home-librarian who fosters a reading culture for future generations. The platform has brought about benefits to the business owner like more bookings and fewer cancellations, more upselling opportunities for holiday offers, and secure and fast payments.

#### KCB Bank Mobi-reg Portal - 2021 to date

This project seeked to collapse multi-step Bank sector service requests into one complex service-request initiated and approved on a maker-checker model, do Inter-dependency processing. Provide better visibility of complex actions and better experience by giving users the ability to view automatic processing of statuses to individual operations and abstract asynchronous APIs for a seamless experience.

#### **Decalogue International - 2022**

Developed and launched a responsive website for Decalogue International Ltd using Angular framework. Collaborated with the company's team to create a user-friendly interface and experience optimized for site performance. A lot of user testing was carried out to ensure peak overall functionality was delivered.

#### **Gitsearch Web Application - 2018**

This Angular web application uses Github's API to enable a user to search for github accounts. View certain details of an account and public repositories and maneuver to live links of the applications or their github repos.

#### **Education**

#### **Moringa School**

June 2018 - January 2019 Software Engineering, specialized in Web development and Java + Android Development

#### **KCA University**

September 2016 - April 2018 Studies in Computer Science

#### Kanunga High School

2012 - 2015

Kenya National Examination (KCSE)

### **Knowledge and interests**

#### Languages

English: Native speakerKiswahili: Native speaker

• German: Basic in word and writing (A1 Level)

#### **Technologies**

Angular , React , Vue , Javascript / Typescript , HTML & CSS , Bootstrap & Material UI beautifiers , Android , Git Version Control (Git) , Java , REST APIs , Docker , Kubernetes, Firebase & PostgreSQL databases

#### **Interests**

 Art - my greatest passion and strength is in fine art. It has also helped me build moral excellence such as patience, keenness and creativity which have played a major role in my software design